Contact

shelbygs@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/shelby-scarbrough-rn (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Highly self-motivated
Exceptional writing skills
Able to grasp complex processes
and explain in laymen terms

Shelby Scarbrough, RN, BSN, CBS

Risk & Quality Reviewer, Nurse Analyst, Healthcare Quality Improvement, HEDIS RN Reviewer

Greater Houston

Summary

A Registered Nurse with extensive experience in the medical field, with a focus in Healthcare Quality Improvement, HEDIS Projects, Risk and Quality Management and Legal Litigations. Experience includes medical record review, on-site audits, research, analytics, patient care planning and intervention. Additional experience in Managed Care with Medicare Advantage Plans. Focused and supportive team player with excellent time management skills, adaptable and a quick learner.

Experience

US Anesthesia Partners Risk Reviewer June 2018 - July 2020 (2 years 2 months) Houston, Texas

- Review anesthesia records to ensure the standard of care is met for all reported incidents via

hospital report, provider report or patient complaint from all Greater Houston area Methodist, CHI

Baylor St. Luke's, Memorial Hermann, HCA Houston Healthcare, OakBend and East Texas Tyler

hospitals as well as many Ambulatory Surgery Centers (ASC).

- Conduct site visits for all newly acquired ASCs to ensure compliance with federal, state and US Anesthesia Partners guidelines for staffing, anesthesia machines, medications, equipment, discharge criteria, insurance, etc.
- Contact patients who have requested a call back for medically related questions.
- Active member of the Continuous Quality Improvement committee that meets monthly to discuss reviewed cases and track trends with Anesthesia chiefs and partners from all platforms that we serve.

- Run weekly reports, for my colleagues, of all open cases to ensure that they are reviewed in a timely manner and that no case falls through the cracks.

WellCare Health Plans
Temporary HEDIS Reviewer QI Specialist RN, BSN
October 2017 - May 2018 (8 months)

Houston, Texas

- Abstract, data-enter and over-read medical records, in accordance with HEDIS guidelines.
- Utilize the following databases: PseudoClaims, Change Alert, QSHR and Centauri.
- Proficient in MS Word, MS Excel, MS Access, MS Outlook and Skype for Business.
- Created numerous shortcuts for a more efficient workflow and re-vamped PseudoClaims Data Entry Tool.

Shook, Hardy & Bacon L.L.P.

4 years 5 months

Nurse Analyst

February 2013 - September 2016 (3 years 8 months)

- •Work extensively on medical chronologies.
- •Analyze medical records, provide scientific literature and formulate alternative causations for attorneys to settle lawsuits for Fortune 50-500 companies.
- •Collaborate with attorneys regarding cases prior to depositions and mediations.
- •Generate billable time revenue for the firm by working on a multitude of global litigations.
- •Track record of zero cases going to trial that I worked on for over 4.5 years

Temporary Nurse Analyst

May 2012 - February 2013 (10 months)

Shook, Hardy & Bacon, LLP

•Perform the same roles as above but as a temporary employee.

Cigna-HealthSpring

Practice Coordinator II

January 2009 - January 2011 (2 years 1 month)

HealthSpring Life & Health

•Educate providers (MD's, PA-C's, and NP's) on Texas HealthSpring Guidelines.

- •Prep charts for providers displaying patients' measures that were due and input measures into company's program, Ascender.
- •Track Admits/Discharges from hospitals, SNF's and Rehab in order to prevent future admissions.
- •Run reports for measures due and worked with clinical staff to meet Texas HealthSpring Guidelines, HEDIS and STAR measures.
- •Attend monthly Practice Coordinator Meetings and Annual Summit as well as various training sessions.
- •Providers received 100% of their bonus while working with me (98-99% accuracy achieved on my interim and year-end audits)

UTMB

Research Assistant I – Research Associate II January 2002 - January 2009 (7 years 1 month)

University of Texas Medical Branch, Departments of Psychiatry & Behavioral Sciences; Otolaryngology; Pharmacology and Neuroscience & Cell Biology

- •Order laboratory supplies and reagents, organize and maintain lab to facilitate a cohesive working environment and facilitate communication between labs and vendors.
- •Act as a liaison between labs and Animal Resource Center.
- •Maintain all medication records and highly hazardous materials for the lab and Pharmacy.
- •Train graduate students on proper lab techniques and protocols.
- •Perform surgeries on the rodent model, obtain DNA from specimens, run PCR to genotype and perform laboratory assays according to protocols.
- •Extract, embed and cut tissue on cryostat and sliding microtome.
- •Perform immunofluorescent staining on brain and spinal cord tissue.
- •Capture images on fluorescent and confocal microscopes, via Quality One Imaging and Metamorph Imaging Programs.

New Graduate Nurse

Education

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston Bachelor of Science, Nursing · (2000 - 2002)

National University

Master of Forensic Science (coursework completed; thesis pending)